<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>/publication-type/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>/publication-type/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A general class of two-sample statistics for binary and time-to-event outcomes</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/bg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/bg_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; We propose a class of two-sample statistics for testing the equality of proportions and the equality of survival functions. We build our proposal on a weighted combination of a score test for the difference in proportions and a Weighted Kaplan-Meier statistic-based test for the difference of survival functions. The proposed statistics are fully non-parametric and do not rely on the proportional hazards assumption for the survival outcome. We present the asymptotic distribution of these statistics, propose a variance estimator and show their asymptotic properties under fixed and local alternatives. We discuss different choices of weights including those that control the relative relevance of each outcome and emphasize the type of difference to be detected in the survival outcome. We evaluate the performance of these statistics with a simulation study, and illustrate their use with a randomized phase III cancer vaccine trial. We have implemented the proposed statistics in the R package SurvBin, available on GitHub (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MartaBofillRoig/SurvBin)&#34;&gt;https://github.com/MartaBofillRoig/SurvBin)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision tool and Sample Size Calculator for Composite Endpoints</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/bcg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/bcg_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article considers the combination of two binary or two time-to-event endpoints to form the primary composite endpoint for leading a trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It discusses the relative efficiency of choosing a composite endpoint over one of its components in terms of: the frequencies of observing each component; the relative treatment effect of the tested therapy; and the association between both components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We highlight the very important role of the association between components in choosing the most efficient endpoint to use as primary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For better grounded future trials, we recommend trialists to always reporting the association between components of the composite endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common fallacies to note when using composite endpoints: i) composite endpoints always imply higher power; ii) treatment effect on the composite endpoint is similar to the average effects of its components; and iii) the probability of observing the primary endpoint increases significantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
