<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 | MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication-type/3/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication-type/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>3</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication-type/3/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>NCC: An R-package for analysis and simulation of platform trials with non-concurrent controls</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/kb_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/kb_2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Platform trials evaluate the efficacy of multiple treatments, allowing for late entry of the experimental arms and enabling efficiency gains by sharing controls. The power of individual treatment-control comparisons in such trials can be improved by utilizing non-concurrent controls in the analysis. We present the R-package NCC for the design and analysis of platform trials using non-concurrent controls. NCC allows for simulating platform trials and evaluating the properties of analysis methods that make use of non-concurrent controls in a variety of settings. We describe the main NCC functions and show how to use the package to simulate and analyse platform trials by means of specific examples.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Adaptive Discard Graph for online error control</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; In recent years, graphical multiple testing procedures have gained popularity due to their generality and ease of interpretation. In contemporary research, online error control is often required, where an error criterion, such as familywise error rate (FWER) or false discovery rate (FDR), shall remain under control while testing an a priori unbounded sequence of hypotheses. Although the classical graphical procedure can be extended to the online setting, previous work has shown that it leads to low power, and other approaches, such as Adaptive-Discard (ADDIS) procedures, are preferred instead. In this paper, we introduce an ADDIS-Graph with FWER control and its extension for the FDR setting.   These graphical ADDIS procedures combine the good interpretability of graphical procedures with the high online power of ADDIS procedures. Moreover, they can be adapted to a local dependence structure and an asynchronous testing setup, leading to power improvements over the current state-of-art methods. Consequently, the proposed methods are useful for a wide range of applications, including innovative complex trial designs, such as platform trials, and large-scale test designs, such as in the evaluation of A/B tests for marketing research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Online Closure Principle</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The closure principle is fundamental in multiple testing and has been used to derive many efficient procedures with familywise error rate control. However, it is often not suitable for modern research, as more flexible multiple testing settings are considered where not all hypotheses are known at the beginning of the evaluation. In this paper, we focus on online multiple testing where a possibly infinite sequence of hypotheses is tested over time. At each step, it must be decided on the current hypothesis without having any information about the hypotheses that have not been tested yet. Our main contribution is a new online closure principle which ensures that the resulting closed procedure can be applied in the online setting. We prove that any familywise error rate (FWER) controlling online procedure can be derived by this online closure principle. In addition, we demonstrate how short-cuts of these online closed procedures can be obtained under a suitable consonance property and apply the results in order to construct new online multiple testing methods. Finally, the new online closure principle is used to derive an improvement of the currently most promising online procedure with FWER control, the ADDIS-Spending under local dependence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the use of non-concurrent controls in platform trials: A scoping review</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/bh_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/bh_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Platform trials gained popularity during the last few years as they increase flexibility compared to multi-arm trials by allowing new experimental arms entering when the trial already started. Using a shared control group in platform trials increases the trial efficiency compared to separate trials.
Because of the later entry of some of the experimental treatment arms, the
shared control group includes concurrent and non-concurrent control data. For a
given experimental arm, non-concurrent controls refer to patients allocated to
the control arm before the arm enters the trial, while concurrent controls
refer to control patients that are randomised concurrently to the experimental
arm. Using non-concurrent controls can result in bias in the estimate in case
of time trends if the appropriate methodology is not used and the assumptions
are not met. In this paper, we faced two main objectives. In the first, we
aimed to identify the methods currently available for incorporating
non-concurrent controls, clarify the key concepts and assumptions, and name the
main characteristics of each method. For this purpose, we systematically
searched research articles on methods to include non-concurrent controls. The
second objective is to summarise the current regulatory view on non-concurrent
controls to clarify the key concepts and current guidance. Therefore, we
conducted a systematic search in regulatory guidelines regarding using
non-concurrent controls and summarised the most relevant arguments and
recommended methods. Finally, we discuss the advantages and potential caveats
of using non-concurrent controls.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of Trials with Composite Endpoints with the R Package CompAREdesign</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/cbg_2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/cbg_2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt; 
Composite endpoints are widely used as primary endpoints in clinical trials. Designing trials with time-to-event endpoints can be particularly challenging because the proportional hazard assumption usually does not hold when using a composite endpoint, even when the premise remains true for their components. Consequently, the conventional formulae for sample size calculation do not longer apply. We present the R package CompAREdesign by means of which the key elements of trial designs, such as the sample size and effect sizes, can be computed based on the information on the composite endpoint components. CompAREdesign provides the functions to 
assess the sensitivity and robustness of design calculations to variations in initial values and assumptions. Furthermore, we describe other features of the package, such as functions for the design of trials with binary composite endpoints, and functions to simulate trials with composite endpoints under a wide range of scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision tool and Sample Size Calculator for Composite Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/bcg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/bcg_2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This article considers the combination of two binary or two time-to-event endpoints to form the primary composite endpoint for leading a trial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It discusses the relative efficiency of choosing a composite endpoint over one of its components in terms of: the frequencies of observing each component; the relative treatment effect of the tested therapy; and the association between both components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We highlight the very important role of the association between components in choosing the most efficient endpoint to use as primary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For better grounded future trials, we recommend trialists to always reporting the association between components of the composite endpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common fallacies to note when using composite endpoints: i) composite endpoints always imply higher power; ii) treatment effect on the composite endpoint is similar to the average effects of its components; and iii) the probability of observing the primary endpoint increases significantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
