<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Werner Brannath | MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/author/werner-brannath/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://academic-demo.netlify.app/author/werner-brannath/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Werner Brannath</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Werner Brannath</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/author/werner-brannath/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An exhaustive ADDIS principle for online FWER control</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; In this paper we consider online multiple testing with familywise error rate (FWER) control, where the probability of committing at least one type I error shall remain under control while testing a possibly infinite sequence of hypotheses over time. Currently, Adaptive-Discard (ADDIS) procedures seem to be the most promising online procedures with FWER control in terms of power. Now, our main contribution is a uniform improvement of the ADDIS principle and thus of all ADDIS procedures. This means, the methods we propose reject as least as much hypotheses as ADDIS procedures and in some cases even more, while maintaining FWER control. In addition, we show that our principle cannot be further uniformly improved. Finally, we apply the new principle to derive uniform improvements of the ADDIS-Spending and ADDIS-Graph.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Adaptive Discard Graph for online error control</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/journal-article/fbb_2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; In recent years, graphical multiple testing procedures have gained popularity due to their generality and ease of interpretation. In contemporary research, online error control is often required, where an error criterion, such as familywise error rate (FWER) or false discovery rate (FDR), shall remain under control while testing an a priori unbounded sequence of hypotheses. Although the classical graphical procedure can be extended to the online setting, previous work has shown that it leads to low power, and other approaches, such as Adaptive-Discard (ADDIS) procedures, are preferred instead. In this paper, we introduce an ADDIS-Graph with FWER control and its extension for the FDR setting.   These graphical ADDIS procedures combine the good interpretability of graphical procedures with the high online power of ADDIS procedures. Moreover, they can be adapted to a local dependence structure and an asynchronous testing setup, leading to power improvements over the current state-of-art methods. Consequently, the proposed methods are useful for a wide range of applications, including innovative complex trial designs, such as platform trials, and large-scale test designs, such as in the evaluation of A/B tests for marketing research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
