<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 on MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>/publication_types/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3 on MBofillRoig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision tool and Sample Size Calculator for Composite Endpoints</title>
      <link>/publication/bcg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bcg_2020/</guid>
      <description>Summary points: - This article considers the combination of two binary or two time-to-event endpoints to form the primary composite endpoint for leading a trial. - It discusses the relative efficiency of choosing a composite endpoint over one of its components in terms of: the frequencies of observing each component; the relative treatment effect of the tested therapy; and the association between both components. - We highlight the very important role of the association between components in choosing the most efficient endpoint to use as primary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new approach for sizing trials with composite binary endpoints using anticipated marginal values and accounting for the correlation between components</title>
      <link>/publication/bg_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bg_2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Composite binary endpoints are increasingly used as primary endpoints in clinical trials. When designing a trial, it is crucial to determine the appropriate sample size for testing the statistical differences between treatment groups for the primary endpoint. As shown in this work, when using a composite binary endpoint to size a trial, one needs to specify the event rates and the effect sizes of the composite components as well as the correlation between them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>