<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new approach for sizing trials with composite binary endpoints using anticipated marginal values and accounting for the correlation between components</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/bg_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/bg_2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Composite binary endpoints are increasingly used as primary endpoints in clinical trials. When designing a trial, it is crucial to determine the appropriate sample size for testing the statistical differences between treatment groups for the primary endpoint. As shown in this work, when using a composite binary endpoint to size a trial, one needs to specify the event rates and the effect sizes of the composite components as well as the correlation between them. In practice, the marginal parameters of the components can be obtained from previous studies or pilot trials, however, the correlation is often not previously reported and thus usually unknown. We first show that the sample size for composite binary endpoints is strongly dependent on the correlation and, second, that slight deviations in the prior information on the marginal parameters may result in underpowered trials for achieving the study objectives at a pre-specified significance level. We propose a general strategy for calculating the required sample size when the correlation is not specified, and accounting for uncertainty in the marginal parameter values. We present the web platform CompARE to characterize composite endpoints and to calculate the sample size just as we propose in this paper. We evaluate the performance of the proposal with a simulation study, and illustrate it by means of a real case study using CompARE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection of composite binary endpoints in clinical trials</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article/bg_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/journal-article/bg_2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The choice of a primary endpoint is an important issue when designing a clinical trial. It is common to use composite endpoints as a primary endpoint because it increases the number of observed events, captures more information and is expected to increase the power. However, combining events that have no similar clinical importance and have different treatment effects makes the interpretation of the results cumbersome and might reduce the power of the corresponding tests. Gómez and Lagakos proposed the ARE (asymptotic relative efficiency) method to choose between a composite or one of its components as primary endpoint comparing the efficacy of a treatment based on the times to each of these endpoints. The aim of this paper is to expand the ARE method to binary endpoints. We show that the ARE method depends on six parameters including the degree of association between components, event proportion, and effect of therapy given by the corresponding odds ratio of the single endpoints. A case study is presented to illustrate the methodology. We conclude with efficient guidelines for discerning which could be the best suited primary endpoint given anticipated parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
