<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on MBofillRoig</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on MBofillRoig</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of phase III trials with long-term survival outcomes based on short-term binary results</title>
      <link>/publication/bsg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bsg_2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Pathologic complete response (pCR) is a common primary endpoint for a phase II trial or even accelerated approval of neoadjuvant cancer therapy. If granted, a two-arm confirmatory trial is often required to demonstrate the efficacy with a time-to-event outcome such as overall survival. However, the design of a subsequent phase III trial based on prior information on the pCR effect is not straightforward. Aiming at designing such phase III trials with overall survival as primary endpoint using pCR information from previous trials, we consider a mixture model that incorporates both the survival and the binary endpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A general class of two-sample statistics for binary and time-to-event outcomes</title>
      <link>/publication/bg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bg_2020/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: We propose a class of two-sample statistics for testing the equality of proportions and the equality of survival functions. We build our proposal on a weighted combination of a score test for the difference in proportions and a Weighted Kaplan-Meier statistic-based test for the difference of survival functions. The proposed statistics are fully non-parametric and do not rely on the proportional hazards assumption for the survival outcome. We present the asymptotic distribution of these statistics, propose a variance estimator and show their asymptotic properties under fixed and local alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision tool and Sample Size Calculator for Composite Endpoints</title>
      <link>/publication/bcg_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bcg_2020/</guid>
      <description>Summary points: - This article considers the combination of two binary or two time-to-event endpoints to form the primary composite endpoint for leading a trial. - It discusses the relative efficiency of choosing a composite endpoint over one of its components in terms of: the frequencies of observing each component; the relative treatment effect of the tested therapy; and the association between both components. - We highlight the very important role of the association between components in choosing the most efficient endpoint to use as primary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new approach for sizing trials with composite binary endpoints using anticipated marginal values and accounting for the correlation between components</title>
      <link>/publication/bg_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bg_2018/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Composite binary endpoints are increasingly used as primary endpoints in clinical trials. When designing a trial, it is crucial to determine the appropriate sample size for testing the statistical differences between treatment groups for the primary endpoint. As shown in this work, when using a composite binary endpoint to size a trial, one needs to specify the event rates and the effect sizes of the composite components as well as the correlation between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selection of composite binary endpoints in clinical trials</title>
      <link>/publication/bg_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/bg_2017/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: The choice of a primary endpoint is an important issue when designing a clinical trial. It is common to use composite endpoints as a primary endpoint because it increases the number of observed events, captures more information and is expected to increase the power. However, combining events that have no similar clinical importance and have different treatment effects makes the interpretation of the results cumbersome and might reduce the power of the corresponding tests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>